Hi, everyone.
This is Nikhil and Padmashree.
We are the Adobe student assistants
from the MLK library,
and welcome to the
Adobe XD Basics Workshop.
Today, we're going to work through
creating a simple yet elegant website,
which could also work as a presentation,
or a pitch deck based on
your required mode of storytelling.
By learning these tips and tricks
not only will we all become amateur
UI UX designers,
but also be able to put forward
your ideas, and visions for products,
and systems in the world.
For this project,
we will be making a short presentation
on the business model of Uber.
So before we get started,
like any good design product,
it's extremely important
to get a set of background work done
- before getting into our final product.
We start with the research work.
As we are making short a presentation
on the business model of Uber,
we make sure we understand
the interesting aspects of their
past, present, and future.
Once we have collected our resources,
we summarize it down
to the bullet points we want to convey,
and use it as part of our storyboard.
Now comes the interesting part.
We sketch out in a super rough way,
what we want
our final product to look like on paper.
It's important not to miss this part,
as this will give us an anchor
when diving into the multiple features
that Adobe XD offers,
which sometimes can make us
want to do everything at once,
and lose our vision.
What we want to capture here is what
the visual feel of the information
needs to be like,
and the flow of information
so that it makes a coherent story.
It may take a
few tries and multiple
scratched up papers to get through it,
but trust me, guys, it's worth
knowing what you're up to
before you dive deep.
Once we have our research work
and structure
in place, it's time to type out
our information.
Adobe XD has a super sweet feature
of being able to drag
and drop text into its location.
Hence, it requires
a little bit of formatting beforehand.
All text needs to be saved in plain
text or simple text mode.
So wherever you type out
your text makes sure your output
is in .txt format.
Another important thing to keep in
mind is to have your headers
and body text in separate folders.
Now these will be formatted differently,
so you would like them
to be grouped together.
What do you see being done here is
we're just taking out
all the headings, putting them together,
bring the text into a new file.
And even though we have bullet points,
we'd like to have them as paragraphs
for Adobe to read them as a single unit.
So just removing all kinds of enter
or line spacing
so that we get modular text,
which can be read as separate
chunks of information.
This may seem a bit
laborious up front,
but it saves a lot of time later on.
So hopefully you guys can incorporate it
into your process.
Now we move on to
how to store the information.
What we want to do
is make sure that all our assets,
including the text file, or pictures
or any videos are in their own folders
and preferably labeled in the order
in which they appear.
What Adobe wonderfully does
is if you have multiple boxes,
you can drag all these pictures
and it will populate individual boxes.
And now,
we're ready to start on our project.
If you guys are following along,
make sure to download all the files
from the Google Drive and extract them
onto your local computer.
Only once they're extracted,
can they be dragged
and dropped into the Adobe XD files.
So let's just get a head start on that.
Once you have all of these done,
we can make sure we have
installed to the newest update
and open it up
so we can start on our project
in the next video.