Before we get into the tutorial,
let's just go through the slides
we're going to create
for Uber.
We've got a cover page,
a menu, and a few slides of content.
What we see here is a clean cover page,
with just a logo and some text on it.
The menu page
has the major topics that we're going
to be covering in the presentation,
which when clicked upon,
take us to the respective slides.
Our first content slide is the company
profile,
where we've created the timeline
of the company's existence.
As this is just a short tutorial,
the second page jumps
directly into the future of Uber,
elaborating on the company's
plans for their future.
I'm sure you guys
will have many more slides in between.
But here the last topic we cover,
is the Roadmap to 2040.
Here, we have more sub topics
which, when clicked upon
elaborate on each subheading.
A slightly advanced thing we touch upon
is to create responsive buttons
so pages
can be linked within each other.
Now that we know what we're up
to, let's get right into it.
As soon as we open
Adobe XD, we land in the startup menu.
Here we have an option to choose
from their layouts,
or open a preexisting saved file.
For the purpose of this recording,
let's choose the web layout
with 1920x1080 resolution.
If you guys are used
any Adobe product before,
we should land on a similar layout
with all our tools on the left hand side
and the property menus
on the right hand side
with our working space in the center.
What we see here
is the first page of our website,
or slide deck known as the artboard.
Now you can change the color
of the artboard by the fill option here,
which sets the tone
for your presentation.
As we're working on Uber, which works
basically with white and black,
we're going to keep it a minimal
white background.
What's really important
here is to make sure to label
your artboards
as we create multiple slides.
It's important that we keep track
of which slide goes off to which,
for which you can either
double click on the name
right above the artboard
or change it in the layers panel.
At this point,
we'd like to create multiple artboards
to work on simultaneously.
Now, if you have some layout
and formatting done on the first artboard,
it's best to use the “command D” or
“control D” function to duplicate your artboards.
Since we have
three different pages
apart from the menu page
and the color page,
we're going to duplicate it five times.
You can figure out the number of slides
you need,
by referring to your initial wireframes sketches.
Another way of doing this
is to go to your artboard option
on your left hand side and then choose
the size of the artboard we need next,
when the formatting of the next slide
is totally different from the first one.
Another sneaky method you can use,
is to always click
on the name of the artboard,
and then hold “alt” or “option”
and drag the artboard to the place
you want it to be.
For visual clarity,
let’s just select the artboard’s -
the last three of them and drag them below.
So we've got the cover, the menu,
and then the main slides.
Let's also get onto renaming them
quickly,
before you move on to the next steps.