Now we’re onto creating the
rest of our pages.
So as we learned
before we select the page
we want to duplicate,
and then “Control + D” or “Command + D”.
But oops, we don't really want
the menu and its items to be duplicated.
So we're just going to “Control + Z”
“Command + Z”, which is undo.
And then on the first duplication,
let's just remove the content
and then duplicate that slide.
So we've got the menu icon we wanted
and we've got the guidelines
which make sure we maintain uniformity
and create a beautiful visual system.
We brought them back
to the initial location that they were.
So we've got the cover page, menu page,
and now finally making sure
that all our next artboards
have the names that reflect
what the menu page calls them.
Moving on,
we're going to check out another cool
function of XD.
So these are called components.
You see on the left hand
panel near the layers panel, the box
or you can right
click on it and go to make component.
The other option is to go
“Command or Control + K.”
Let's just check out what it does.
So we select the component,
copy, and paste it into the next artboard.
Here we center
it just above the guideline
so that it becomes the title of the page.
So what's interesting
now, is if you click
on the original component
and make any changes in it,
you see that
it's reflected in its copies.
So let's say you want to change
the name of the slide later on.
You just go to the menu page
and change the main component,
and all of its copies
will reflect the change.
As we
start designing our company profile,
we know from our wire frame
that we want a timeline
where there's a central line,
and then we have elements on the top
and the bottom.
So let's start off by using the tools
and drawing a line in the center.
Make sure to hold “Shift”
while drawing the line
so that it's perpendicular
or horizontal, so it will be 90 degrees
or zero degrees based on
whichever side you're closer to.
Let's use
the properties on the right hand side.
Make sure it's clicked and
then the property panel is activated.
Coming back to use the magical repeat
grid option.
So we created text blocks.
You got the right kind of setting
we want.
So we've got headings and
we've got body text. So create the,
make sure that the heading
is slightly bolder, slightly bigger.
And the next text box,
which is the body text, is slightly
smaller, lighter, easier to use.
Even if you have fancy
text in the heading,
have relatively simple
text for the body.
So use like a Sans Serif,
Works Sans, Open Sans, Sans works well.
So once you have your text
boxes in place, select
both of them and click on repeat grid.
This time, instead of the vertical,
we’ll choose
the horizontal control buttons.
So as we drag it out, we've got
as many as we need.
I think we need five.
So let's stop there and for the heading,
bring in your heading text file.
Just drag it and make sure
that it is extracted in case
you're using the Uber file as non
extracted files won't be populated.
So you've got your headings
and your heading spaces,
and then you've got your
body text and the body box.
So just
make sure all the body text fits.
If you find it difficult
for the body text
to be fitting into the drawn box,
make sure you use the controls.
Here are about restricted height,
restricted width,
fixed width, I'm
sure for different needs.
You guys will figure it out
as you use it,
play with it.
And once we're done,
we make sure we just had elements
we need and ungroup them,
and then we move around the text
so that it's in the right place.
Alternating top and bottom,
and we bring in
the icons, scale it down.
You can scale together by making sure
you select all and then scale them down.
And we've almost got the company
profiles.
It's always a good habit
to kind of group the icon and the text
related to it.
So when you adjust things around,
then move together.
It also helps with the alignment
functions that we’ll learn shortly.