We're now going to
learn about the prototyping function of XD.
This is what makes any kind of UI / UX
software special.
It makes sure
that our sense of storytelling
is more than just linear, right?
And we can move around.
We can click around,
have parallel story lines running.
For this, we need to make sure
that we're in the prototype window.
You can find this
after the design window
at the top left corner of your screen.
Now, the prototyping window
is used to make sure
that all the links and connections
between different elements
in the slide deck or in the presentation
in the website is created.
How we do this is by clicking
on the element that we want to link,
and you can see
on the right side of the element.
You get a blue arrow mark.
When we click and drag the blue arrow mark.
You see a link, a connection, an arrow being made.
Now this can be either
an element to a page
or even a whole page to a page.
So if you want
anyone to click anywhere on the page
and it goes to the next page,
make sure you click the artboard
and the artboard gets a small arrow marked
link that to the next dartboard.
We made sure that all our menu
icons link back to the menu page
and all the elements of the menu,
link to the slides.
At this point, Nikhil
shared the document with me, Padmashree.
So he just went to the share option up
there and added -
invited me to edit.
So when you work in groups,
this helps a lot.
So on my end, when I received
the invitation, I just make sure
I went to Creative Cloud notifications
and clicked on the latest notification
Let's let it load
I'm the new teammate
and owner of the file.