Yep, so we're going to start with
the future of Uber.
If we refer back to our wire frame,
we know that there is a short
brief under each topic.
So what I did was hold “Alt”
and then drag down the text.
Because I realized that the
“Future of Uber” was actually a component,
I right click on it
and then set ungroup component.
And then let's just format it
to the way we like.
Have it slightly lighter, more easier
to read, and center aligned.
So once I choose a color
for my secondary text,
I know that it's a color
that I'll be using again and again.
So an interesting thing to do is to
maybe add it your swatches
by clicking on the plus
button in the color panel.
For the content of the page,
I know that we're going to approximately
have similar formatting.
Have the title and subtitle of the page,
so I select them both while
holding shift.
Make sure that the title
is no longer a component,
by ungrouping component.
And then I left align
both my text boxes
within the text function
and then left align
both the text functions to each other.
Now this can be done
by using the align functions
at the absolute top of your property
panels.
As I want them both aligned to the left,
I choose the fifth option.
I also know from our wireframes
that I want these to be bullet points
that are linked together,
so let's just add shape next to it.
For that, I'm
going to choose the rectangle.
I could also just press
“R” on my keyboard.
Choose the color I want.
And go back to the repeat grid tool.
So just make sure it's in the right
place, select all my items
holding shift or dragging over it
and press on the appropriate function.
I need three bullet points,
but that would be the spacing required,
so I'll just make sure
I've got my spacing checked
and bring in the elements
from my folder.
So bring in my .txt files of the header
to the first header of the group
and the .txt of the first body copy
to the first body
copy text box of the group.
So to make sure that all
the bullet points seem connected,
I'm using the line tool,
which is on the left hand side toolbar,
connecting all of them
and using the properties
on the right hand tab
to make it a bit darker.
Use the colors there
and increase the thickness of the line.
Now with Importing images,
while we can directly
just drag and drop,
you have to come in and scale it again
and see how that works.
So a better habit is to use
the rectangle to draw the shape
where you want the image to be
and then drag your image into that box.
And what this does is gives you a frame.
And when you double click
into that frame, you can adjust
how you want the picture to sit within
that frame.