Creating
the icons or clickable elements is part
of the magic of components.
Now this is slightly advanced and
you don't have to worry about it
immediately,
but it's nice to have when you have XD.
So this is a bit more than beginners.
This is intermediate.
So what you want is just the images
and the colors of the boxes.
So we're just going to click into
the groups,
by holding down control or command.
So that lets us select
the options directly of a group.
Or we can just select them from the layers
panel as I do rectangles.
Now we all want them to be
slightly smaller, so they can be part of
the screen.
Let's just bring it down
to 120 “Width” and “Height”
and now select the images
and bring them on top of the rectangle,
so that they sit in-between.
Now we immediately see the problem that
we can't see their backgrounds behind,
which is why we use the magic
of “Layer Styles”. Now Layer Styles,
essentially,
lets us choose how an image
or a layer interacts
with its background.
If we choose multiply,
only to darker aspects of the image
show.
So here the darkest aspect
being the icon itself,
the white disappears.
And after we've come to this point,
let's just try to rearrange it bit
make sure that the images
are center of the box,
We can either do it by eye measurement,
the guidelines, or use align functions.
After that, get - make sure that they
appear in the right place on the screen,
because this is a repeating element
that we'll use again and again.
I feel like the border is a bit too
thick, so going to reduce that a bit,
and maybe
even reduce the intensity of the shadows,
and looks good. At this point,
we make the icons into a component.
Now this is super important to create
some kind of reaction to the clicking.
So let's select all aspects of the image
and the background,
and click on component
on the right hand side
- or “Command / Control + K”. Just right
Click on it
and find “Make Component” order.
We're gonna quickly
go into the prototype window
and make sure all the icons are linked
to the respective pages. Now
because they’re components, when we copy
paste these into the next sheet,
they retain their connections.
So what I'm going to do now
is go back to the design screen,
select all of them, “Control + C”
and “Control + V” into the next sheet.
Right.
So we see, except for the first one,
all of them are already linked to
which screen that's supposed to go to.
So we'll just quickly select
the first option, the leaf
and connect it back to the screen
it's supposed to go to
when clicked upon.
Now we've got an awesome
animation creation,
So you want it to react,
you want to give the person feedback
that it has been clicked upon.
So what we do is we work with states,
so click on the component.
And on the right hand side
where we added it as a component,
click on the plus button
and go to toggle state.
So toggle state
is what happens when you click on it.
Let's edit the component
while it's still in the toggle state.
So just keep an eye that is in
the toggle state in the component panel.
Now what we're going to
do is click into the component
instead of a shadow,
give it an inner shadow.
So instead of drop shadow,
it's an inner shadow.
And then maybe you could change
the background so that it's a lighter
green,
even reduce the capacity of the image.
So it looks a bit pressed.
It's - it's used,
and now we've got a button.
So if you go back, I'll zoom out
and click outside, click
back in in the component.
Try seeing it in the toggle state, non toggle
state, toggle state, default state.
It looks good.
Awesome.
Now this is something you could repeat
on the other buttons.
But for now,
let's just go back to the preview.
Check out how we're doing.
So that's the preview - the play button.
We start with our call page.
Click anywhere to go into menu.
Let's just click on Future of Uber.
That’s a clean page.
Click Anywhere Again to go
into the next page, which is Road Map.
Now we haven't yet completed this,
but let's click
on first Button,
and that's great animation.
So it leads to its own page.
Just a little bit
more hard work, and work done.
And here's is the final product, guys.
I'm sure all of yours look so cool.
I’ll be excited to see it again.
Clicking on your option,
going to your company
profile,
the future of your company.
Use hover states.
Just try it out and clickable buttons. Yay.